What's going on everybody?
Before we get started, do want to say
it's a great day to be a Raider. That's
one of the things MD says all the time.
Um, and as we're starting to build this
culture, um, starting to build this new
organization of ours. Uh, culture starts
with people and we're reminded about
that all the time. And um we have
probably the best staff in the world and
I want to take this time on behalf of
John Spitech, our leadership team, th
myself by Starky and Patch. Uh we want
to take a time just to thank a couple
people before we get started. Um
and really uh we went into this weekend
to try to acquire 10 great players. Um
welcome 10 new picks to the dark side
and it took a lot of miles. It took a
lot of miles. uh covered a lot of miles,
a lot of time away from families. And
that starts with our scouts. Um I want
to start off uh thanking Calvin Branch,
Kyle
Kyle Cabalero, Ryan Gravel, uh Matt
Anne, Jay Hill, and uh Greg Ravini. Uh
going to our national group, uh Lenny
McIll, Andy Dingler, and uh Stigs.
uh the pro department, you know, kind of
on on the on the outskirts of this
process and they do a great job of
keeping us just wired on like the needs
of teams and just helping out with the
ghost list. Uh that's Ben, Jordan, and
Jordan and Jordy. Um then our scouting
assistants,
uh Pat P, Zach, and Megan. Um, and to
get into the CAP group, uh, we're really
thankful for Tom Delaney and his group
with, uh, Julia and David. Uh, we just
had an awesome, uh, postdraft free
agency process. And I'm sure you guys
will get the names, but uh, they did an
outstanding job of keeping us wired,
keeping us, uh, keeping it tight, you
know, allowing us the resources to do
what we do. And we're thankful for that
group uh to get into the analytics group
uh Canal and company uh with the model
uh Andrew Jonah and Walt um they
definitely challenge us this whole
entire process you know uh we're going
through
um doing our traditional methods and
they will you know go out of the way and
dig some people out and give us some
challenges and it was awesome uh the
work that they did and helped uh just
make sure our board and everything was
in alignment And uh I know a lot of
people have seen uh we probably have the
number one uh draft room in the world. I
know you guys saw it going into the
draft. It's awesome. And a lot of that
wouldn't be um made possible without uh
Brad Gooberry and Dustin Cader and what
they did uh with that room. Man, it made
this thing so fluid and so easy. Um I
know every time I got a phone call like
people saw the room, they just saw the
back of the room. they saw the big logo,
but like on the screens, uh, it was
really, really, really awesome. It kept
us really organized, and we're really
thankful for them. Um, our security
team, Bob Steridi
and, uh, Ron Connelly, just, uh, making
sure they helped us out with all of the
background checks and all the
information. I know BY is backing down
in his office all the time. Um, and they
did an awesome job of helping us out
with the reports. and to the equipment
group. We had uh all the people in for
our top 30s this year and um as they're
working their way through the building,
they helped us out um through this whole
process. So that's Bob, Coach Adam, uh
Mo, Aiden, Devonte, and Nick. And then
the video group like we said just as
this scouting process has turned um
technology with our system um just easy
access video um it wouldn't be made part
without this group uh Jason Craig Caleb
and Nelson um and to get into our ops
group we talked about the uh the top 30s
and the visits uh they did an awesome
job of just coordinating the logistics
of getting the guys in and out of this
building um and that's Derek, Danny,
Daniel and Carter um to get into the uh
engagement group, obviously Rob D, uh
First Lady Chznney and uh Dr. Casey. And
then uh to get into the medical staff,
right, we brought in a lot of players.
We want to get some extra looks on some
guys and they did a great job of
organizing that. That's Cortez, Alec
Guerrero, all the docs, Drew, Tim,
Lamar, and Scotty. Um and then the
cafeteria, you know, we had pretty much,
you guys saw three-day eat fest, but
we've been eating forever. This whole
entire month, we never needed for
anything. I'm obviously thankful for the
resources with the ownership group, but
um Angelica
and Ricky and uh Dante Moose, that
group, the whole entire staff, they're
doing an outstanding job. They're in
here before us. They're out here after
us, and we're really thankful for that.
Um and then of course the coaching
staff, right? We talk about alignment.
Um these guys came fresh off a world
championship and went right to work um
to help us continue to our future of
getting to our next one. And um that's
Clint Andrew Janokco
um Robbie Joe D and that entire staff.
They did an awesome job of just all of
the hard work. You know, we got our we
got our staff in the building right now.
We got our players working on the
players. They take time away from that.
Go right to the right to the scouting
reports. Right when they got here, we
put them right on free agency. um their
families are flying in trying to find
places to live and uh they did a great
job of helping us um aligning this group
and just helping us with the vision um
of of our fearless leader John Spych. Um
obviously we want to say thank you to to
you guys obviously the media and um to
Will staff uh Cam uh Joseph Jade and
Ashley. And then, you know, as we're
talking about uh the ground that we
covered, uh I just want to talk about
obviously the reports. We did 3,926
reports this year that netted these 10
picks. Um I think that's that's that's a
number that is very very big and a whole
lot of work that goes into these 10
picks that are going to come support the
future of this organization. And we
think that's a really really special
thing um to welcome these new dudes to
the dark side. So, uh, with that, we'll,
uh, take questions on this group.
>> I mentioned to Stark privately the other
day that I had two college head coaches.
I asked them if anything was different
this year about the evaluation process,
and they said that the Raiders both
mentioned private from each other,
scouts were probably the best listeners
this year, more than they've ever been
in the best of all the NFL. Was that
something that you guys specifically
targeted to encourage them? Maybe
teaching more about listening was or is
it just happened to be it got noticed
this year?
>> That's a cool observation, Hondo. Um I
think that's a critical part of being a
great scout is being a great listener
and asking the right questions and
giving space to get the information and
make your own interpretation of that
information. So that's a really cool
observation. I mean, that's something we
prioritize for our scouts is figuring
out what questions to ask and and also
being receptive to the information, too.
Um, so that's a cool observation for
sure. And appreciate you guys hanging
with us. Be Hunt had a laundry list of
uh Grammy acceptance thank yous. So, he
did a great job. Um, and you guys are
the true grinders who are hanging it out
on day three. So, appreciate you guys.
Just to echo what he said, too.
>> What went into the decision to trade for
McCoy as far as from a a health
standpoint? you were confident enough to
do that.
>> Go ahead.
>> Yeah. So, confidence um was not a
problem. You know, we felt good about it
at at where we took them and it was
opportunity to get value. Um this is
probably arguably the best corner in the
draft and um we feel like we have great
great people and a great process to um
make sure we get the best out of this
player.
>> I was just going to echo that just I
have a lot of confidence in the player
and our medical staff is outstanding
here. So just echo what B. Hunt said,
Alex Go, Chris Cortez, our doctors.
We'll have a great plan in place for him
and like you said, he's a he's a high
quality person and football character
makeup, too. So it
>> you guys are you guys anticip uh he told
us on the Zoom call that is he's leaving
it to you guys to determine whether he
needs additional surgery on the knee. I
was wondering, have you guys made a
decision on whether he will get another
procedure?
>> Yeah, so right now, you know, before he
even gets with our people, we didn't
didn't even get that far. Um, we have a
great medical staff, like we said, uh,
uh, uh, Cortez and Alex G. U, we're
going to get in the building, make all
those decisions, but right now we're
really excited about celebrating this
kid and, uh, getting him in the
building. He's 20 years old, he's
twitchy, he's fast, he's a cover guy,
he's got some punt return skills, and
we're really excited to see what he does
and um, the future's bright for this
guy.
>> Just to follow up on that, he said he
also said that you guys had a Zoom call
uh, with him the day before the draft. I
was wondering, did you guys have it like
kind of a sense that there was a shot of
him potentially falling falling in the
draft ahead of time?
>> Yeah, that's a fair question. Um, and we
do our diligence on every prospect. I
would say he wasn't the only one. We did
a Zoom with this this week. We touched
base with a lot of players. We do a lot
of confirmation calls too to make sure
their information, their contact
information is accurate. But there are a
group of players that we zoom this week
just to follow up and touch base because
you have the ability to use three Zooms
with each player just and we're
continuing to get to know these guys and
that's a really critical part of our
process is just all the different touch
points you can have. So we did Joe
Woods, our corners coach, and our DC
Robbie Leonard Zoomed him this week. Um,
and again, it wasn't just him, but it
was a lot of players. Were you kind were
you guys shocked that he failed this far
to day three? This was someone um that
was considered even with the knee
concern a top potential top 10 pick.
Were you guys were you shocked that he
got this far in the draft? Think
>> that that was the thing that had us most
excited about moving that one pick? You
know, um we say it all the time. uh you
go into day two, you go into day three
at the top where we are, you know,
people have time to kind of chew on it
overnight and we felt like this was a
player that 32 teams or so we're going
to look at and have he'd be the same guy
up on the board that kind of stuck out
like a green thumb. We didn't want to
take an opportunity take a chance on
missing on.
>> For both of you, Mike Washington, that's
a terrific running back when you watch
him on film. Were his value was higher
than where you were able to pick him.
Are you guys Was it like Christmas when
you're sitting there with that pick and
he's still on the board?
>> Yeah, I mean we were excited to get him
for sure. 6'1,
225, 43, ran for over a thousand yards
this year. Super productive, high
character. Yeah, we were really excited.
We feel like he's a really good fit for
coach Scubiaak and and Andrew's scheme
um in the wide zone system. So, pretty
fired up about him and the person he is,
too.
>> It's awesome. This guy's going to
generate explosives for us and just
another weapon that's going to add to
our offense and uh Clinton Janoko are
going to do a great job of utilizing him
and help us score the football.
You
>> mentioned character and evaluating him.
It seems like a common theme among a lot
of your picks both this year and even
going back to last year is the
character. Um intelligent, smart, that
that factor. How much does that play
into your evaluations when you're
looking at players?
>> Go for it.
>> Yeah, it plays a lot. like um we that
was our theme this whole entire process
through the draft. It's been our theme
in free agency. That's been our theme uh
the whole time. We had a u a shield
system where we were looking and we
wanted to dawn uh
put a shield on some players. Um we have
different tiers and and this we wanted
to make sure that we not only get the
best players uh that are going to come
in here and be awesome contributors on a
team, but they're going to be great
people. Like I said when we started, we
talking about the culture. Um the
culture is driven by these people that
we bring in and it it was awesome to get
a person like this to add to the group.
>> When it comes to the X's and the O's of
it all, it seemed like the other theme
was the versatility of a lot of the
different players. How important was
that as well?
>> Yeah, that was critical, especially in
the secondary. Um a lot of the guys we
had in the secondary group can play
different spots between Traden Stuks,
Dalton Johnson, Zeke, um and Jamad, too.
Um all those guys are pretty versatile.
They've played nickel, they've played
deep, they've played outside. Even
Stukes has played outside corner in his
career, too. So, it really helps,
especially we're going to have a pretty
versatile scheme under Robbie Leonard.
So, that's a critical component, too.
>> What went into the decision to move on
from Tyrie?
>> Yeah. Go ahead. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, we were just going to say just
um it was just an opport opportunity for
a fresh start. Um fresh start for him,
fresh start for us. Um, you know, the
phone's ringing the whole entire draft
and where we were um when the when the
phone call rang, we were looking at
where we were as a team. We're looking
at the decisions that we've made, free
agency decisions we made in the draft
and we thought it'd be an awesome
opportunity for him, awesome opportunity
for us. Uh, we wish him all the best.
You know, we're thankful for his
contributions as a Raider and we think
he'll do a great job uh for uh New
Orleans.
>> Yeah, I'll just speak to that, too. I
was fired up just because we moved up to
get Dalton Johnson. So that trade
allowed us that opportunity. We have a
lot of conviction and belief in Dalton
Johnson's ability to play defense and
special teams, too. So that was pretty
exciting for me as a college scouting
director.
>> B, your your main focus is pro
personnel. When you look at these
rookies, several of these guys, they're
physically they're not guys that have to
come in, get bigger, faster, stronger.
They're already there. From a pro
personnel perspective, how personally
are excited are you? because a lot of
times with rookies, you look at what
they can become, but some of these guys
are ready to play right now.
>> Yeah, it's pretty awesome. You know, uh
Hondao, I know, uh I'm glad you did the
research. I do have my PhD in pro. Uh
but, you know, I've been doing uh
college since I've been in the league,
which is pretty awesome. And it's really
exciting to uh get these players that
are ready to play. You know, when we're
looking at these guys and we're looking
at evaluation, we're looking at their
ceiling and their floor. A lot of these
guys have really high floors. Um, we
really think that a lot of these these
guys are gonna be ready to come in and
contribute and come in and compete. You
know, the main thing we're looking at
was to try to get as many many people
that we can to compete on every level in
every room just to bring up the
competition in every room. Um, so it's
super exciting.
>> How did the process come about that you
ended up with two of the secondary
players from Arizona with Trayon Stu,
Sam Dalton Johnson? Were they targets
all along? was is something that you saw
and how much you think they'll help each
other build through the process of being
rookies together.
>> Yeah, we're excited about both. Um it
was a cool circumstance that they're
both from Arizona and I would say we
have a cool relationship with their head
coach too, Brent Brennan. Our assistant
GM Brian Stark worked with him in the
past, too. So, we had great information
on those guys in addition to Kyle and
Lenny going through Arizona. But we had
a pretty clear vision for both those
players and affinity for them separate
from them as a package deal. Um we would
have been interested in both players at
different spots, but we're really
excited to add both those guys.
>> With both of those guys in particular,
uh you know, what were they tasked with
in that um Arizona defense that you
think is really going to translate well
for you guys?
>> Yeah, that that defense when you study
it, it's pretty cool. Danny Gonzalez,
their defensive coordinator, they're
very versatile with how they use those
players. All three safeties got picked
today. Um, which is really unique in
itself, but all three of those guys have
played different spots. You'll see
Dalton roll down and play big nickel.
You'll see Traden play a lot of nickel.
He also plays deep. And same with the
other player, too. So, it's really cool.
You know, there's a certain level of
football intelligence those guys have to
be able to handle those that amount of
duties and tasks. comes with the current
landscape of college football obviously,
but you drafted a lot of guys that
transferred from, you know, school to
school. And I know that's not brand new
for you guys, but how much more
attention to detail when it comes to
scout evaluating do you have to do in
terms of, you know, getting to know a
player, not just for where he went to
school, where he succeeded, but also the
other locations as well?
>> Yeah, it's the cool thing about our
scouts, man. like um I think
historically
uh back in the day really you're getting
a late start um cuz these guys have been
there but but we're getting to know
these guys right away you know um these
the we talked about I mentioned our area
scouts right away the area scouts get
all the background um from the totality
of their career so um let's say a guy
played his junior season at Clemson his
senior at Penn State um we're going to
have we're going to talk to Jay Hill in
a draft and say hey how did he do what
was the story for his first three years
there and then um we're going to talk to
Ryan and say hey uh what was your
thoughts at Penn State and see if those
things match up and we kind of just
because like you said where we're at now
with not only these co kids but also the
portal kids this is pretty much every
single player whereas back in the day we
might punish a guy for that like where
were you going why did you go what was
the reason and now just with NI and
everything it's it's pretty common with
with a lot of these guys so we it's it's
us it's up to us to get with the picture
and and That's the get with that being
the new normal.
>> What do you think Brandon Cleveland
really fits in with what Rob wants to do
on the interior of the defense?
>> Yeah, we're excited about Brandon
Cleveland. He's u been a multi-year
starter at NC State. He's a strong,
heavy-handed
uh player that plays the run well. He's
got initial quickness and we really like
his makeup, too. So, we're excited to to
add him into that group and see him
being able to play on all three downs.
for both of you. When you watch Kiron,
this is a guy you got, you literally
have to remember he's only been playing
five years. When you look at that bend,
I mean, I'm going to show my age. I'm a
lot older than both of you, but he's
just almost like a Stretch Armstrong
type guy. What when you see that and
then you think about only playing five
years, where's your mind go when you
think about where he can end up?
>> Man, it's super exciting. Uh when you
look at this dude, you just see upside
cuz he's so green. And the most exciting
thing about Robbie is like you know that
you're going to everything you teach him
is going to be new and and he doesn't
have any bad habits if that makes sense.
Um this guy is a football lover first
and foremost. He's violent. Um he can
rush a passer and he can smack guards
and uh he's going to take on pools and
set the edge. Um when I was in
Philadelphia uh we took a player similar
to this. It was Jix Hunt um with a
similar kind of background and um he's
done a great job for them and and I
really believe Kei can do the same
thing. Plus,
>> maybe a two-part question, one for
clarification. Looks like you guys
signed Matazawa after the draft. Is that
an IP signing or is is that how that
would work?
>> Yeah, so we're still processing those
UDFA um contracts. So, I probably
shouldn't comment on those until they're
official, but I would say he is IP
eligible. And he was he was a really
productive kicker for Hawaii. So, we'll
probably wait until that becomes
official just by the league rules. But,
yeah, he he is to confirm that.
>> So, would you as you go into the draft
now, you have you have a plan, you have
needs, you have best available players.
Like, there's a a balance of trying to
figure that out. when you made a plan
for the draft, how closely were you guys
able to, you know, fill the needs that
you wanted to address the the, you know,
getting best available players that are
on your board and all those things in
terms of sticking to what you wanted to
do uh going into the process.
>> Yeah, I think we had an awesome process.
Um,
Spy laid laid out the vision for us. Um,
and the cool thing is he pretty much
lets us cook and and do our job. And,
uh, I feel like, you know, today we won.
Now, it all starts on Thursday with
rookie mini camp. We're going to get get
a chance to see. But, um, I think we
put, like we said before, we got
competition in every room. Um, we're
really excited to see these guys get
with with the vets and and see where
we're at. But, today we feel like we did
an outstanding job.
>> After adding after adding four, I
believe it's like four defensive backs
in this year's class. I was wondering,
how do you guys feel about the current
depth in not only just safety, but in in
the quarterback room as well?
>> Yeah, we really wanted to add
competition at every level. Um, super
excited about the guys we we added
today, the undrafted free agents that'll
compete too, and then the guys we have
coming back. Um, so really the intention
was to add some competition and add
speed in those rooms and add a level of
toughness and special teams value.
>> Can you all talk about what you saw in
Malik and what role he could play for
this offense and kind of just the wide
receiver room all all together?
>> Sure. Yeah, Malik's a guy who ran I
think 437. Um, so he's got a vertical
speed element to him on the outside.
He's really good on crossing routes,
over routes. We feel like he can get
open on the move. And then he's had
special teams production over his
career, too. Um, he returned a punt for
a touchdown this year. He had a high
punt return average this year. So,
really excited about him and his ability
to stretch the field on the outside.
>> It was really cool with him. For me, he
averaged 16 point 16.7 yards a catch and
I think he had like five um catches over
40. So, we're just talking about
explosives, right? Trying to find more
field stretchers, guys make more
explosive plays and open up this
offense.
>> Do you feel like he fits kind of
Fernando's skill sets with him being
able to hit those kind of back shoulder
throws, contested catches, type plays?
>> Sure. Hell yeah. Absolutely.
Gentlemen, if if id have told you coming
into this draft you were going to get
Trey Zoo at 91, I think both of you
would have thought I was an idiot, but
that's where you were able to get him.
You guys loved him. You were on him
early. You stayed on him. When you turn
on the film and you look in the fourth
quarter and he's 25 yards downfield
still with that energy, his stamina
level, would you just talk about a the
gift of him at n at 91 and his freakish
athletic ability, please? Yeah, we talk
about football lovers, right? And um you
know, being a former lineman myself,
when I see stuff like that, it's really
exciting. Um this guy can play every
position on the field, which is great.
Um I think I heard Spy say in in in
I'm sorry, Spy and Starky said all he
does is does his job and he blocks
everybody. Uh we got a chance to see him
live playing against Miami and um they
had a couple rushers go in the first
round and uh he did a good job against
them and it's really exciting uh to see
what he does and adds to this room. Like
I said, we're trying to add multiple
people to this room uh that are violent,
that are football lovers, that are big
people and he's one of those guys we're
really excited about.
That's good.
Thanks a lot.
>> Thanks guys. Appreciate you.